Okay. So, let's think about what we need to change to make this simulate
حسناً، لنفكر فيما يجب علينا تغييره لنجعل هذا يحاكي
a full yahtzee rolling system with five dice instead of just three.
نظام متكامل لرمي الياتزي بخمسة أحجار نرد بدلاً من ثلاثة فقط.
Well, first, we need to declare those two variables,
أولاً، نحتاج إلى تعيين هذين المتغيّرين،
dice four and dice five,
dice4 وdice5،
and we set them by calling the function rollDice.
ثم نحدّد قيمتيهما باستدعاء الدالة rollDice.
So now, we call this function rollDice five times simulating five different dice.
نستدعي الآن هذه الدالة rollDice خمس مرات لمحاكاة خمسة أحجار نرد مختلفة.
And again, inside the while loop,
ومرة أخرى، داخل حلقة while،
we call them five times updating the variables dice four and dice five as well.
نستدعيها خمس مرات لتحديث المتغيرين dice4 وdice5 أيضاً.
Every time we roll all five dice,
في كل مرة نرمي فيها أحجار النرد الخمسة كلها،
we update our count variable by one,
فإننا نزيد 1 إلى قيمة متغيّر count،
because it means one single roll for all the five dice.
لأنه يعني رمية واحدة لأحجار النرد الخمسة كلها.
And lastly, we need to update our while loop condition here.
وأخيراً، يجب علينا تحديث شرط حلقة while هنا.
So instead of just checking if dice one is the same as dice
فبدلاً من التحقق إن كان dice1 يساوي dice2
two and dice two is the same as dice three,
وdice2 يساوي dice3،
we also check that dice three is the same as dice
نتحقق أيضاً إن كان dice3 يساوي dice4،
four and dice four is the same as dice five.
وdice4 يساوي dice5.
All that is surrounded by these parentheses that have a not signed before it,
وذلك كله محاط بهذين القوسين مع وجود علامة NOT قبلهما.
which means the while would continue to loop as long as this is not true,
هذا يعني أن حلقة while ستستمر في الدوران طالما بقي هذا الشرط غير صحيح،
which means as long as the five dice are not a match.
أي طالما لم تتطابق أرقام أحجار النرد الخمسة.
Notice that I didn't have to say explicitly that dice
لاحظوا أنني لم يكن علي أن أقول حرفياً
five is the same as dice two because that is implicit.
أن dice5 يساوي dice2 لأن هذا معلوم ضمناً.
If that condition happens and
إذا تحقق ذلك الشرط
the condition happens and that condition happens and that condition happens,
وتحقق ذلك الشرط وتحقق ذلك الشرط وتحقق ذلك الشرط،
that implicitly saying that all five dice are a match.
فهذا يعني ضمناً أن جميع أحجار النرد الخمسة متطابقة.
Also, on a small side note,
أيضاً، كملحوظة جانبية صغيرة،
notice how I had this written in two lines instead of just one.
لاحظوا أنني كتبتُ هذه العبارة على سطرين بدلاً من سطر واحد فقط.
This is just to make it easier to read.
فعلت هذا فقط لتسهيل قراءتها.
Usually, it's okay to put new lines in
لا توجد مشكلة في العادة في وضع سطور جديدة
the middle of commands in Java as long as it doesn't
في وسط الأوامر في Java ما دامت لا تبطل الأمر،
So for now, don't worry about if you have to write long commands in one single line.
لا تقلقوا في الوقت الحالي حول إن كان عليكم كتابة أوامر طويلة في سطر واحد.
But as a side note,
لكن كملحوظة جانبية،
you can do something like this.
يمكنكم القيام بشيء كهذا.